okay so let's see the rob quiz solution
so we do need the rob tool remember the
program order that's the only place
where the program order is preserved
between the issue which is done in
program order and the commit which is
also done in program order because
things in between are they're out of
order so we definitely need the Rob for
that to temporarily store the
instructions result yes the Rob holds
the instructions result between the time
when it is produced meaning when we are
actually broadcasting it on the bus and
the time when the instructions result is
committed to the register file so we
definitely have that role for the Rob to
serve as the name or the tag for the
result yes with tomasulo's algorithm the
reservation station was playing this
role but with the Rob the Rob entry is
really going to serve this role for an
instruction to store the source operands
until dispatch know the reservation
station still will retain this role
basically the reservation station still
stores the source operands until
dispatch so this answer is not correct
and to determine which instruction goes
to which execution unit again Rob
doesn't play this role the Rob is
usually unified meaning all of the
instructions go to the same Rob they
just get different entries in it we know
which execution unit the instruction
should go to because different execution
units have different reservation
stations so when we issue an instruction
we send it to the right set of
reservation stations and that determines
what is going to be the execution unit
so this answer is also not correct